hello and welcome to video number one
and we're going to talk about starting
your own wordpress affiliate system
so first things first i want to talk
about the video course as a whole and
then we'll talk about the things that
you will need and then of course we'll
jump straight in
okay so this is obviously video number
one video number two will be the video
after this one and that will be about
planning
your affiliate program so in other words
before you go out and you set up an
affiliate program or you worry about
like the wordpress plugins you really
need to sit down and figure out what is
it
in a program that you want or
maybe you need to sit down with an
affiliate and ask them what is it that
would appeal to them of course we'll
dive in deeper in that particular video
video number three will talk about how
to map out your affiliate funnel
so we're gonna take all the information
that we planned and brainstormed in
video number two
and we're gonna map it out
via a flowchart system you can use a
mind map software you can use anything
just to allow you to see the structure
video number four we're going to talk
about the different affiliate wordpress
plugins that are out there and that are
available to you and of course video
number five we'll talk about add-on
plug-ins so in other words besides the
core
affiliate program that should be able to
track
everything so that your customers your
affiliates can come they can send you
know prospects to your site and then
they get credited besides that core
there's a lot of different features that
you can add on and we'll talk
more about that in that particular video
video number six and seven is gonna be
the setup process so we're going to take
pretty much everything that we
brainstormed and we talked about in
videos two three four
and five
and show you how to set everything up
step by step so in fact the setup
process is actually a lot easier so once
you have an idea of what affiliate
program you want
then it's going to be a lot easier
now in terms of what you need
we're going to assume that you already
have a wordpress site created already
and we're going to assume that your
product or service is currently being
sold on wordpress in other words you're
using something like a ecommerce plugin
like woocommerce or a cart system
in order for the wordpress affiliate
system to make sense you have to be
selling something on your wordpress site
right if you're using a third-party cart
system and you are not really selling it
on your wordpress site rather you're
selling it let's say on a third-party
site then it doesn't really make a lot
of sense and
so you really have to
if you haven't created the site yet you
really have to think how can i sell it
on the site how can i use something like
woocommerce or something similar or a
wordpress membership site and sell
something on the site if that makes
sense and then of course last but not
least you will need to have some money
to purchase the wordpress plugins
you're not going to need a lot but you
will need enough to
at least get a
one site license all right with that
said let's move on to video number two